In this video I will give you little bit more insight into the syllabus
在这个视频我会给帮你 更深入地了解教学大纲
of EX101x - what are we going to do together.
的ex101x - 我们在一起该干什么。
Well, we're going to work on data analysis - I guess you understood so much -
好了，我们要工作，数据分析 - 我猜你知道这么多 -
but I will tell you what we will do: in the first
但我会告诉你我们将做些什么： 第一
six weeks we will work with spreadsheets only. I will teach you
6周我们将与电子表格电子表格 s 而已。 我会教你
all the things you need to know about spreadsheets - we will address
所有你需要知道的事情 电子表格电子表格秒 - 我们将解决
Pivot tables, array formulas, how to test your spreadsheet,
数据透视表 S， 数组公式 ，如何 测试电子表格 ，
VLOOKUPs, all the things you need. And some people, while I was designing
纵向查找(vlookup)函数 ，你需要的所有东西。 而有些人，当我设计
this MOOC,
这MOOC，
asked me the following question: why spreadsheets? Why are you going to spend
问我以下的问题：为什么 电子表格电子表格 你为什么要花费
six weeks on spreadsheets?
六周电子表格电子表格
Especially in the era of big data, aren't you supposed to be teaching those people
尤其是在大数据时代，不 你应该教导那些人
Hadoop clusters or 'R'? Well, no!
Hadoop集群或'R'？ 哦，不！
Spreadsheets are really relevant! One of the reasons that is very important
电子表格电子表格 为真正相关的！ 其中有一个非常重要的原因
is that they're very commonly used: ninety-five percent
是因为他们被十分普遍的使用： 95％的
of all US companies still use spreadsheets for financial reporting.
美国公司仍然使用电子表格来代表财务报告。
so is everyone else. Working with spreadsheets is
所以就是所有其他的人。 有工作 电子表格电子表格是
workers use spreadsheets in their daily life. This is a survey
工人在日常生活使用电子表格电子表格。 这是一个调查
from the US Labor Statistics
来自美国劳工统计局
from 2003, so it's a little bit old but it's still
从2003年，所以这是一个有点老，但 它仍然
a lot of people. And a more recent survey, from 2009,
很多人。 和最近的调查显示， 从2009年开始，
showed that spreadsheets are the fourth most common task
显示电子表格电子表格 为第四 最常见的任务
that people do at their job on the computer,
人们在做他们的工作 计算机，
after using Internet and Word Processing, so
利用互联网和Word后， 处理中，所以
it's really, really common. And what happens often is that spreadsheets are
这是真的，真的很普遍。 经常发生的是， 电子表格电子表格 s为
designed as a one-time solution -
设计为一次性的溶液 -
you think I'm only going to use this spreadsheet
你以为我只会用这个 电子表格
for this one report. You just download the data,
这一份报告。 你刚才下载 中的数据，
make a graph and this is where it will end. And often it doesn't!
作的曲线图，这是在那里将 结束。 而且往往不！
You know, you have that guy at the next desk, and he says "Oh, that's a nice report,
你知道吗，在你旁边桌子的那个人，他说：“哦，这是一个很好的报告，
can I have it as well?" Sure, you are good colleague,
我能不能看看？“ 当然，你是 好同事，
so you email this spreadsheet to him, and he changes some data,
所以你这个电子邮件电子表格他说， 他改变一些数据，
and he adds a few worksheets, and the spreadsheet starts leading its own life.
他增加了一些工作表 ，电子表格开始引领自己的使用生命。
And our research has shown that this is very common - on
而我们的研究显示这是很常见的 -
average spreadsheets stay alive for five years,
平均来说，电子表格可以存活五年，
and during their life span they are used by 12 different people.
在这期间他们会由 12个不同的人使用。
So this is why it's really important to be able to design
因此，这就是它为什么尽可能被设计成
a good, error-free spreadsheet, because even though you think
一个好的，无错误的电子表格 如此重要， 因为即使你认为
it's just for you, chances are very big
它只是给你使用，有很大几率
that this spreadsheet has a very long life-span. So, that's the answer to the
这电子表格有一个很长的寿命。 所以，这就是问题的
why we're doing this course in spreadsheets.
这就是我们为什么用电子表格进行这门课程。